Olivia Gowan

Seaforth, ON

Phone: (519) 301-0119 | Email: olivia.a.gowan@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oliviagowan/ | GitHub: https://github.com/Olivia-the-G | Portfolio: https://olivia-gowan-portfolio.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with experience using multiple programming languages and an aptitude for learning. Adept at maintaining a cohesive workflow and paying strong attention to detail. Motivated by complex projects that require lots of problem solving and learning on the job. Interested in pursuing a career in Back End Development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical Languages: JavaScript | CSS | JQuery | Express.js | Sequelize | Mongoose ODM | React.js

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: University of Toronto, Toronto, ON An intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, ReactJS, and GraphQL.

PROJECTS

Blogger - Full Stack

https://github.com/Olivia-the-G/blogger | https://blogger-like-frogger-59f0220c1556.herokuapp.com/

- CMS-Style tech blog with login functionality
- All code written by myself
- Handlebars, CSS, Javascript, Sequelize, Express/Express-session, doteny, Bcrypt

Hungry Mikey - Full Stack

https://github.com/Olivia-the-G/Hungry_Mikey | https://hungry-hungry-mikey-f614bbce79a1.herokuapp.com/game

- Fun and educational game for children to learn about nutrition from "Mikey" a character used from the newly public domain short film "Steamboat Willie"
- Primarily implemented the backend functionality routing, crud operations, database connection, models etc. Also did some CSS and handlebars on the front end.
- Handlebars, CSS, Javascript, Express, Brain.js, JAWSDB, dotenv

Thoughts on NoSQL - Back End

https://github.com/Olivia-the-G/thoughts-on-NoSQL

- Web API back end application for a social media website
- All code written by myself
- Javascript, Express.js, Mongoose (MongoDB), Moment.js

EXPERIENCE

Annie's Seafood Restaurant, Stratford ON — Server, Kitchen hand

December 2023 - PRESENT

- Handle large cleaning projects, providing the best results for the restaurant owner
- Use problem solving and critical thinking to take charge in completing difficult work tasks
- Display adaptability and flexibility when working under pressure to carry out jobs

The Braai House, Stratford ON — Hostess

August 2023 - November 2023

- Managed and coordinated reservations and provided support for serving staff
- Practiced teamwork and good communication with coworkers to maintain efficient work flow and at times took on leadership roles where organization was a key element for success

Addserv Janitorial Ltd, Monkton ON — Commercial Cleaner

November 2022 - PRESENT

- Clean offices 100% independently, managing time constraints and meeting client standards
- Show attention to detail and self advocacy in all aspects of the job while working independently
- Handle large amount of responsibility, working unsupervised to uphold company standards